Hey everyone, it's Richard. You're
watching The Plain Bagel. Welcome to
Investment Analyst Reviews Investing
TikToks part
12 or 30. Not so sure anymore. We've
done a couple of these at this point and
the more I do the the more of myself I
lose. The
harder it is to keep track of time. Uh
today we'll be covering some finance
TikToks as per usual and I've been
inspired to revisit the platform with my
recent video on prediction markets
having stumbled upon a new genre of
finance TikToks, prediction market
traders. People talking about how to
make money on platforms like Kalshi and
Polymarket. And as you'd expect there's
been a lot of uh juicy content that
that's come with that. Uh now for those
new to the channel, welcome. My name is
Richard. I'm a registered portfolio
manager. I manage investments for a
living. I'm a CFA charter holder and CFP
professional. And today we'll be
covering some finance TikToks to give
our input and thoughts, a general review
of the TikToks uh with the hope of
trying to be constructive. There are a
lot of great TikToks out there. There's
also a lot of sketchy or uh more
reckless stuff. So in parsing through
this, my hope is that we walk away
knowing a bit more about finance and
economics uh with the input we give. A
quick thank you to today's sponsor
Blinkist. Stick around for a free trial
and exclusive discount code. And without
further ado,
let's hop into it.
>> I'm a full-time Polymarket trader and a
lot of people don't understand how you
can make a full-time living on
Polymarket, but let me explain. So
Polymarket, it's just prediction markets
and a lot of people think prediction
markets is gambling, but it's not
gambling. It's predicting based on news,
based on information, and having an
edge.
>> So just quickly for the uninitiated,
prediction markets, this relatively new
platform or at least in the current
sense that we know them, where people
are allowed basically, mostly in the US,
to bet on pretty much anything. Uh you
have contracts on everything from will
Jesus return to do aliens exist. A lot
of sports betting basically happens on
these platforms. Uh but it's also being
presented as a way for people to make
money, right? To bet on things that you
have an edge or insider information on,
well,
>> [laughter]
>> hold on.
So, you're not supposed to it's very
much illegal and and that's one of the
big controversies around prediction
markets, but that's how some people are
using the platforms. The problem is that
A, these platforms, while they argue
that they're a financial exchange, so
they shouldn't be subject to gambling
laws, they just advertise themselves as
a casino basically. That's how a lot of
their marketing comes across. And B,
when it comes to people talking about
how profitable it is to trade on the
platform, we have some data on that and
it turns out that most people lose
money. It's very similar to day trading
in that sense where yes, some people
might make money with the practice, on
average people
don't.
>> Here's one market I'm in. Will Trump
release Epstein files by December 19th?
Every news article is saying that
Trump's DOJ won't release the full
Epstein files on Friday as required by
legislation, but they will release a
partial batch. Easy 10% gain. That's how
easy it is. It's prediction markets.
You're just You're just placing trades
based on the news and the information
that you have. And the information that
we have currently is that they are going
to release some Epstein files today. And
then you just repeat that process with a
bunch of different markets and you make
a lot of money. Join my Discord if you
want to learn more about Polymarket.
>> So, listen, these types of prediction
markets are very young. Yes, there might
be some sort of mispricing or arbitrage
opportunity that sophisticated traders
are able to take advantage of, but
there's no edge with this strategy,
right? This guy talks about trading with
an edge.
He doesn't have any insight into the
Epstein files, right? He's He's using
very general news headlines. And that
might make it sound appealing, right?
This guy made a quick 10% off of a very
likely outcome. But you have to realize
that the way prediction market contracts
work is if you're betting on high
probability events,
you have a capped upside, in this case
10%,
but a fairly large downside of 100% of
whatever you invested. So, if you invest
$100, you could gain $10 or lose the
full $100 you put up. So, there's this
asymmetric profile of returns. Yes, you
might randomly do well if you follow
this type of strategy, but it only takes
a few fails to lose all the money you've
gained if not potentially even more. So,
people really want to get into
prediction markets, you know, that's
totally up to you, uh but I I do view
this as gambling. There's no edge here
you have versus everyone else on the
platform. You're rolling the dice and
the odds might be good on any single
roll, but you're hoping the whole time
that the odd contract doesn't just
completely wipe you out. Given how
rampant insider trading has seemingly
been with prediction markets, you have
to be very careful kind of diving into
the space.
>> This is exactly how you were going to
make a ton of money off of this war
happening in the Middle East if you do
this one thing.
>> Jesus.
Oh, man, what time to be alive.
>> Everybody watches the headlines. Smart
investors watch the contracts, and that
is what you can do, too. Modern warfare
runs on missiles, and missiles are
single-use. And in the first 24 hours of
war, 1,000 missiles were fired. That's
not just strategy, that's inventory that
eventually needs to be replaced, and
fast. So, who builds them? Lockheed
Martin. They're one of the largest US
defense contractors and a major missile
supplier, and they are deeply tied to
government spending. So, when orders
need to be replenished, in this case,
you know, we just had 1,000 missiles get
fired at Iran, then somebody has to
benefit from this as their production
ramps up. This is a long-term investment
strategy. You need to buy and hold for
the next 12 months a little bit of
Lockheed Martin, or otherwise known as
LMT.
>> Sorry.
Long term is relative, I guess. Uh
generally, if you say long term in the
sense of investing,
usually in the industry, we're thinking
five plus 10 plus years, right? Also,
this isn't a good long-term strategy
because you're you're buying a stock off
of a a near-term event, right? Um and
the problem is this video was posted
March 1st.
That's already too late. Yeah, Lockheed
Martin's stock to date has actually
fallen since when this video was posted.
It's actually pretty flat year to date
despite there being two pretty major US
military actions this year. So, that's
the problem with trading off of news
headlines is that unless you have the
nanosecond trading advantage, you not
really going to beat the market trading
off of news headlines because everyone
else in the market is just as aware of
the information that that you're coming
across. Yes, generally defense stocks do
well during periods of turmoil like
this. War alone doesn't guarantee
returns even if they prove to be
beneficial to revenues for the company
because there are many other factors
that are going to influence the stock's
price. You should never invest for the
long term based on near term headlines,
right? You have to understand the
business. You have to know how much
money they make, what they do
outside of just kind of these these very
superficial facts.
>> Don't go get a job. Just do this instead
because before AI completely takes this
over, you can absolutely print doing
this. Go to the Polymarket website and
click on these three lines and then find
leaderboard. This is where you can
publicly see every single top trader on
Polymarket, how much money they're
making and what trades they're taking.
You're going to sort by who's made the
most money in the past week and then one
by one go paste all the top profiles
into chat GPT or any AI. So, these are
proven to be profitable traders. You
already know that they're making money
and now you're just going to copy them.
Ask chat GPT what is the most common
trade taken between all top 50 or top
100 traders that you pasted. So, instead
of just copying one trader who's made a
million dollars, that's going to give
you a consensus of what all the sharp
money is doing. Now, Polymarket is view
only in the United States. If you
actually want to lock in a trade on
Polymarket, you're going to have to
download the Polymarket app. Now, the
only problem with this is you can
download the app and sign up, but once
you do that, you're going to get put
into a line of over 1.1 million people
on the waitlist, which is taking people
months and months to get through. So, if
you don't want to wait in that I'm
about to put you boys on to this
developer invite code DEV20. This code
will let you skip that 1.1 million
person waitlist and immediately get
access to Polymarket in the United
States.
>> So, it's actually a good example of a a
of these prediction markets have kind of
set themselves up with these referral
systems
Um, that get them a lot of not free
marketing but independent marketing I
guess from people like this who talk
about how great Polymarket is
because with that code they actually get
a share of your of your trading fees
that that Polymarket earns. The
marketing side of stuff is really crazy
with prediction markets but you know
this idea of copy trading it's
interesting because we have seen that
with traditional stocks as well. This
idea of just finding people like even
you know Warren Buffett and the like and
just copying whatever trades they do but
when specifically when it comes to
prediction markets there are some issues
to be aware of right? For one these can
be really thinly traded markets. Your
buy orders might move the price quite a
bit and that might be taken advantage of
by people who are being copy traded
especially because with Polymarket a lot
of these traders are anonymous. And two
even if these are successful traders
there's a chance that copying them might
not lead you to having the same return
that they experience
because it only really works if you're
the only one copying their trades which
because this is being posted on TikTok
probably isn't the case. If you have the
successful trader buy a yes contract on
something and then you come in
afterwards and buy that yes contract you
might be following hundreds of other
people who have already bought the yes
contract and bid up the price so that
now you're buying it at a premium price
to what the initial trader bought it for
and then if they sell the contract that
can push the price down. All these
hundreds of people sell their contract
before you get your order fulfilled and
then you're selling low right? Because
now the price is being depressed by all
these orders. And just generally my own
view is that you shouldn't buy
individual stocks unless you understand
the companies. Traditional research we
have is that fund managers aren't
typically able to maintain
outperformance either so following
traders who have done well historically
doesn't mean they're going to continue
to do well. And if you're not someone
looking to invest in individual stocks
then I still don't think copy trading
really makes sense. It's better to go
with a managed solution if you don't
fancy yourself a trader or you know
active investor.
You know, there passive ETFs and things
of that sort that you can look into.
Might be some useful applications of
copy trading, but I think a lot of
people view it as a cheat code of sorts.
There's still a lot of risk and and
things to be aware of. So, I wouldn't
view it that way.
Before getting to the rest of the
TikToks, a quick message for our
sponsor, Blinkist. When it comes to
learning topics like finance or
economics, we all know that beyond
TikTok, books are an excellent resource.
However, personally, as someone with 20
books on my to read list, all of which
have to do with finance or economics,
there's a lot of content that I'm just
likely not going to get to. It's take me
a long time to get through this list,
but that's where today's sponsor,
Blinkist, comes in. Blinkist is an app
that takes non-fiction books and
distills them into 15-minute summaries.
They can read or listen to even if
you're offline, meaning that you can
glean some of the key messages while you
work out, fold laundry, cook food, lose
money on a prop trading firm, any of the
activities you want. You can now also
listen into some of the key lessons of a
book. Personally, I'm a big fan of audio
apps and I view Blinkist as being
supplemental. I've used it to review
books before I read them and to again
touch on subjects that I probably just
won't get to. They have links on great
finance books like The Intelligent
Investor, The Psychology of Money, and
The Little Book of Common Sense
Investing, while also covering a slew of
other subjects ranging from philosophy
to history, science to entrepreneurship.
So, for me, it's a great way to poke my
head out of finance, but if you want to
poke your head in, again, lots of great
content there, too. And with over 9,000
titles, there's a massive collection to
peruse. And the best part is that if you
like to try Blinkist, you can get a free
trial and save an additional 30% by
going to blinkist.com/bagel.
>> Invest in oil right now, $100 will be
$7,523.33
by May
14th. What is such a specific number and
it's like
it's like a week from now.
Like two weeks from now.
Um
How?
>> [laughter]
>> Genuinely. The all-time historic high
for oil prices was $150 per barrel. With
the conflict in Iran, we've seen about a
fifth of the world's oil supply being
impacted by the conflict. There's just
no path for it to to skyrocket by this
ridiculous amount. Even oil producers
are only up about 40% on oil's 80%
roughly year-to-date run. Since it
usually takes time for these businesses
to bolster output. There are some unique
examples, but uh generally speaking it
takes a long time to to sort of ramp up
production. So again, another kind of
bit of nonsense. Also, how does this
have nearly 700,000 likes? This picture.
>> [laughter]
>> I I'm in the wrong field.
I'm clearly doing this wrong. Anyway,
that's enough of a rant on this one
photo. This one picture's got me riled
up, but uh next Tik Tok.
>> Y'all want to learn how to turn your
little tax return into 10, 20, 30, 40,
50,000?
Clock in. I'mma show you how to do it.
Most of you guys don't have a lot of
money in savings, and most Americans
live paycheck-to-paycheck. But, everyone
has tax money coming in, correct? I know
y'all do, especially y'all single moms.
I have single moms that are friends.
They get hella money back. Yeah, I guess
what you're going to do. You're going to
invest it in the stock market, and
you're going to buy tech and AI
companies within the S&P 500. Take your
little two, three thousand dollars you
get from the tax from your tax return,
and you're going to turn that into
30,000. Hi, my name is Britney. If y'all
are new here, sit down. I'mma teach
y'all how to do it. I turned $2,000 into
$110,000
in the stock market. I invested in
nothing but tech and AI companies. I do
not work a 9-5. I am financially free
28-year-old. Um I travel every other
week, and I make a roughly 15 to 20,000
dollars a month profit.
>> She She really uh checked all the boxes
there.
>> [laughter]
>> All the the finance guru uh starter pack
uh checklist.
>> When you get your tax return, you're not
going to spend it. It's the first thing
we're going to do, okay? Second thing
we're going to do, you're going to
download the Fidelity app, okay? It's in
the App Store. It's called Fidelity.
Then you're going to create an account.
Anything that asks you if you would like
to make it a mutual account, mutual fund
account, you say no, okay? You're going
to do the FCASH account. Once you get
that account, it's going to ask you to
verify your social security, all that
stuff, right? Then you're going to
deposit your tax return money into the
app. Then you're going to click the
search bar on the app. Search all of the
stocks that you want to buy, okay? Now,
you're like, "Well, Britt, I don't know
what to buy. I'm I made an account. I
want to start investing. I have my tax
return, but I don't know what to buy."
Invest in tech and AI companies. And if
you don't know the specific tech and AI
companies you want to invest in, click
the link in my bio, the top 20 stocks
that I bought that turned my 2,000 into
over 100,000 is in the link in my bio.
Get that. So then, once you buy those
stocks, okay? You're going to sit on
them.
Yeah, you're going to sit on it. Like I
said, like a savings account. Do not
pull the money. Leave it in there for
like a year.
Six months. Hell, six months, cuz I know
y'all are impatient as hell.
Do six months.
You're going to thank me later. You're
going to thank me. And then your little
two, three, four thousand dollar tax
return you got, yeah. Now you're looking
at it, you're looking at a 20 ball.
$20,000. You're like,
>> The thing is, this is
almost good advice.
>> [laughter]
>> It's so close. And you know, there are
aspects that are good. Like, sure, if if
people are struggling to find money to
invest and they're able to save their
their tax return by not spending on
discretionary stuff, great. You know,
that can be a good starting point.
But really reckless delivery. And you
know, I kind of hate that appealing to
emotions, talking about single mothers,
people struggling, and then talking
about, you know,
10x your money over 6 months while
wearing a fluffy housecoat and talking
about your lavish lifestyle.
>> I was boarding and the week before that
I was in the Dominican Republic and then
in 2 weeks I'm going to Tahiti and Bora
Bora.
>> Also, I don't know where she's getting
this idea of of, you know, again, 10x
your money over 6 months
buying S&P tech stocks. Like, no no
disrespect to the S&P 500, but um you
know, the even the tech sector over the
past 5 years with everything with AI and
the run-up we've seen has only seen and
and I use that term loosely, but only
seen a return of 20% a year, which is
phenomenal. Uh but it's not 10x your
money over 6 months. Yes, some stocks
have done better than that, but
hindsight is 20/20 and chances are
you're not going to know which ones are
going to do that in the future. Just
investing in one sector after it's had
this massive run-up uh is kind of
questionable. And I know some people
might justify it to say, "Look, if this
is what it takes to get people
investing, then maybe you can defend
it." But these high expectations really
set people up for failure, right?
Because if you promise someone, you
know, to 10x their money over a short
period of time, and then they go and
they only earn 10 or even a good 20%,
then oftentimes what you see is they'll
take on more risk to try and achieve the
return that they're expecting from their
investments because that's what they
were told they should experience. Yeah,
she's selling her
stock picks for 20 bucks.
I've actually had the idea of of buying
people's courses and and stock lists
like this and then kind of dissecting
them, um but
I I can't.
>> [laughter]
>> Even for like 20 bucks, it just it feels
like such a betrayal even to to give
that money.
>> If you think about it, you have like
these account sizes where it's $28 for
$2,000 account. Think about the ROI you
can get. And that's why prop trading is
is one of the most popular ways in 2025
to be able to be financial free. And and
I say financially free not in terms of
the millions, but making a $2,000 return
per month is more than enough. Do you
think it's possible? 2% per month. If
you can use a $100,000 account and make
2% per month on your account per month,
that is $2,000 per month. To me, that is
more than enough. I'm not saying that
can, you know, take you around the world
private. I'm not telling you like all
this stuff, but let's take things back
and that's why I want my content to
really resonate with you guys. Is a
little bit is better than nothing and
then once that little bit is consistent,
we compound and increase that little bit
into more over a period of time.
>> So, prop trading, if you aren't
familiar, is when a company gives you
money to trade with and then splits the
returns with you if if you do well. Uh
the way it generally works is there's
kind of two phases. The first is this
qualifier or challenge of sorts uh where
you have to prove that you're a good
trader. There's usually very strict
parameters where if you lose even a
small amount of money, it can disqualify
you. But if you're able to pass the
evaluation or challenge, then you can
get access to a so-called funded account
where the company gives you money to
trade with and again splits the profits
with you. Um which all sounds great for
someone who might be interested in
trading
until you realize that most prop trading
firms make most of their money
from that qualifier fee, from the fee
you pay to try things in a demo account
first because the disqualifier, you
know, factor like the the loss limit or
whatever is so strict. Like it's very
easy to fail. So, a lot of these
businesses are just designed to lure in
suckers on the promise of this funded
account where, you know, you'll make all
this money with very low risk of your
own capital uh when really they're just
making money off of you paying to try it
out. Generally, day trading or or swing
trading even not profitable as it is uh
so you throw in prop trading and you're
just kind of spending money to often
times fail these challenges. And making
2% monthly, it's being presented as this
tame idea, but it would still make you
one of the best investors globally if
you could do that consistently. So,
still not really that reasonable of an
expectation. And of course, this guy has
a a prop trading man. It's ruthless on
Tik Tok. You got to be so careful with
conflicts of interest. Not to say that
someone who owns a business in that
space isn't telling the truth when they
go online and market it.
But it does frame it differently, right?
When you you know that information
listening to them. Whenever you're
consuming content there's three things
to look into. I stole this from the CFA
Institute. They they have a paper called
the Finfluencer appeal. But always look
into motivation so conflicts of
interest, consistency so how their
information matches up to other sources,
and then qualifications, right? What
gives this person the credential to talk
about how easy it is to make money
trading or investing?
And you know, is it provable? Can you
prove that a lady turned $2,000 into
hundreds of thousands? If not, probably
best to move on.
>> The rich don't save cash. They do
something far smarter. And if you don't
learn it, you'll never build real
wealth. Most people think having a big
bank balance means security. They feel
proud when they see cash just sitting
there. But the truth, cash is the worst
place to park your wealth. Inflation
eats it alive year after year. The
wealthy know cash isn't an asset, it's a
tool. They don't hold it, they move it.
They convert it into things that either
grow in value or produce income. Real
estate, businesses, stocks, crypto, and
of course gold. Here's the difference.
Poor and middle class save for comfort.
The wealthy deploy cash for growth. They
let their money work harder than they
do. So if you want to think like the
wealthy, here's what you do. Number one,
keep only what you need in cash for
emergencies [music]
and daily expenses. Two, take the rest
and convert it into assets, especially
ones that survive inflation like gold.
>> Let's keep pushing gold.
>> [laughter]
>> Ah, okay.
That would be why.
Within one tap we we got the answer.
>> Three, remember this rule. Cash loses
value, assets build value. The rich
don't get wealthy by saving, they get
wealthy by owning. And until you shift
from holding cash to holding assets,
you'll always be stuck trading time for
money.
>> So, there are aspects to that that are
true. Yes, once you have things like a
rainy day fund, um you know, as a very
crude gauge of that, 3 to 6 months of
your income
um to cover unexpected expenses and
things like that, then it's a good idea
to look into investing and ways to grow
your wealth uh because getting to your
retirement nest egg or your other
financial goals is a lot easier when you
invest. So, I can kind of get behind
that. But one, there are wealthy people
who do hoard a lot of cash and do prefer
security, right? Just buy things like
treasury bonds or park their money into
savings accounts that are outpacing
inflation to preserve their wealth. And
secondly, when you talk about gold as an
investment class, we we've touched on it
here and there, uh but you have to be
aware that there are risks with
investing in gold. I know some people
have this mental model of gold being
this ultimate asset that is just immune
from risk. But we've had extended
periods where gold's price has decreased
in value even during periods of higher
inflation at times. And I don't even
think it's that popular with wealthier
households. I know that some studies
have shown that stocks and just general
business investments tend to be the
larger share of sort of the the
allocation that wealthier households
have because it's more tangible where
the growth for that money is coming
from, right? If you put $100 into a
business that makes $10 a year, that's
your source of return. Whereas for gold,
you're you're kind of just hoping demand
will continually increase more than
supply, which isn't a guarantee. So
again, generally good to look into
investing once you've covered your bases
from a uh kind of budgeting standpoint,
uh but you know, I'm more partial to
stocks and and taking that more
diversified approach with the investing
rather than just parking all your money
into one asset like gold. Anyway, those
are the TikToks for today's TikTok
review video. Thank you guys for joining
me today. Hope we did manage to make uh
a the content constructive. Again, the
hope is really to have some
information to walk away with. And if
there's any other content or media of
sorts you'd like me to review, feel free
to leave suggestions in the comments
down below. Thanks again for joining me
and as always
be safe out there.